Interview at Swiss Hotel, Istanbul (Turkey) 24 April 2001
Swiss Otelde Ropörtaj, İstanbul (Türkiye) 24 Nisan 2001
Interpreter: How do you reach to all the human beings all over the world?
Çevirmen: Dünyanın her yerindeki bütün insanlara nasıl ulaşacaksınız?
See, there are so many people in this world,
Bakın, dünyada, bu modern zamanlarda
in these modern times, are seeking the truth.
gerçeği arayan pek çok insan var.
So, there are so many false people also in this world
Bu yüzden, dünyada onlardan para kazanmak isteyen
who wants to make money out of them.
çok sayıda düzmece insan da var.
Interpreter:Why the people prefers your way
Çevirmen: Masumiyetiniz ve saflığınız yüzünden mi,
because of Your innocence and the Purity.
insanlar  sizin yolunuzu tercih ediyorlar?
Yes, you have to have the truth, you see.
Evet, sizler gerçeğe sahip olmalısınız, görüyorsunuz.
So they discard what is not the truth and come to me.
Bu yüzden onlar gerçek olmayanı bir kenara atıp, Bana geliyorlar.
Interpreter: How is Turkish people for realisation?
Çevirmen: Türk insanı aydınlanma alma hususunda nasıl?
You are coming to Turkey since last 10 years.
Siz Türkiye’ye son 10 yıldır geliyorsunuz.
Wonderful people. They are one of the best I have seen.
Harika insanlar. Gördüklerim içinde en iyilerden .
When you compare with other countries in the world,
Çevirmen: Dünyadaki diğer ülkelerle karşılaştırdığınızda,
how do you find Turkish people?
Türkleri nasıl buluyorsunuz?
Very good. Excellent.
Çok güzel. Mükemmel.
They are very simple people and innocent.
Çok sade insanlar ve masumlar.
They don’t accept nonsense much.
Saçma sapan şeyleri fazla kabul etmiyorlar.
Interpreter:  There is an economic crisis at this moment in Turkey.
Çevirmen: Şu anda Türkiye’de bir ekonomik kriz var.
Can we overcome this crisis and how can we overcome this crisis?
Bu krizi aşabilir miyiz ve bu krizi nasıl aşabiliriz?
By the grace of God, everything can be work out.
Tanrı’nın lütfu sayesinde, her şey yoluna girebilir.
There are so many realized souls in this country
Bu ülkede o kadar çok aydınlanmış ruh var ki,
that they will be helped very much.
onlara çok yardım edilecektir.
It is most important thing that you have to become very peaceful, joyous and happy.
En önemli şey, sizin huzurlu, neşeli ve mutlu olmanızdır.
Interpreter: Minister who is responsible from the finance of Turkey,
Çevirmen: Türkiye’nin maliyesinden sorumlu bakan,
How do you see him?
onu nasıl görüyorsunuz?
Kemal Dervish, his name is Kemal Dervish.
Kemal Derviş,  adı Kemal Derviş.
Yes yes, I have seen his photograph.
Evet, evet, onun fotoğrafını gördüm.
He is nice man but very hard working.
İyi bir adam ama çok çalışıyor.
So, I think he should take little easy.
Bu yüzden, bence biraz sakinleşmeli.
Because you see, these hard works can make your heart weak.
Çünkü bakın, bu zor işler kalbinizi zayıflatabilir.
So, He is very precious man, he should look after him.
Bu yüzdende, çok değerli bir adam, kendisine bakmalı.
Interpreter:Tonight..the.. you have a big seminar.
Çevirmen: Bu gece … büyük bir semineriniz var.
What will happen to the people who comes there?
Oraya gelen insanlara ne olacak?
I think they will all get their self realizations.
Bence hepsi aydınlanmalarını alacaklar.
Interpreter:Can I have my self realization? She is asking.,
Çevirmen:Aydınlanma alabilir miyim diye soruyor.
Of course, of course.
Tabii ki. Tabii.
It’s a most important thing.
Bu çok önemli bir şeydir.
You don’t have to pay for it. You don’t have to do anything.
Bunun için ödeme yapmak zorunda değilsiniz. Hiçbir şey yapmanıza gerek yok.
But you must respect yourself and go deep down into yourself to know
Ancak kendinize saygı duymak zorundasınız ve değerlerinizin ne olduğunu
what are your values.
öğrenmek için kendi derinliklerinize inmelisiniz.
It is miraculous.
Bu mucizevi.
May God bless you.
Tanrı sizi korusun.
What is it?
Nedir?
Interpreter: She says, “She is feels positive energy,
Çevirmen: “Siz konuşurken pozitif enerjiyi,
love  from you while talking”.
sizden gelen sevgiyi hissediyorum” diyor.
That’s the way thing. We have to Love.
Shri Mataji: İşte bu. Bizler sevmek zorundayız.
Love is the main force
Bizi yaratan, bu dünyayı yaratan
which has created this world which has created us,  we have forgot...
asıl güç sevgidir ama biz bunu unuttuk ..